Guide to the Joel Leivick photographs, 1979-2006 M2039
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Joel Leivick photographs
1979-2006
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Leivick, Joel
M2039
9.75 Linear Feet (3 oversize flat boxes, 1 manuscript box)
The collection consists of photographic prints of travels in Europe, Mexico and the United States - primarily in Connecticut and California; a marble quarry in Carrara, Italy; portraits, and series devoted to gardens.
Scope and Contents
This collection has been organized into five series. Series 1. Carrara Marble Quarry, 1987-1994; Series 2. Europe and Mexico, 1994-2002; Series 3. Rapture, Rome, and the Pantheon, 1987-2006; Series 4. American Travel, 1979-1992; and Series 5. Garden Images, 1987-2006.
Photographs in Series 1 have been printed in The Marble Quarries of Tuscany, published by Stanford University Press, 1999.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University Library in 2014.
Bibliography
Joel Leivick graduated from the University of California at Santa Cruz (B.A.) and Yale University (MFA). After a year at East Tennessee State University, he accepted a position at Stanford University in the Department of Art and Art History. Along with Laura Volkerding, he led the photography program at Stanford and has remained for thirty-five years. Leivick has taught classes in traditional and digital processes including gelatine silver prints, cyanotype and Van Dyke brown printing. His early work was made using a wooden 8x10 view camera with a Goerz double anastigmatic lens and an 8x10 Deardorff camera before moving onto more modern equipment; he most commonly uses a 4x5 view camera when traveling. Leivick works primarily in black and white.
Rome (Italy) -- Photographs; Leivick, Joel; Mexico -- Photographs; Carrara (Italy) -- Photographs; Marble industry and trade -- Photographs; California -- Photographs; Connecticut -- Photographs; Photoprints.; Leivick, Joel; Leivick, Joel
- Series 1. Carrara marble quarry, 1987-1994
  Scope and Contents
  Photographs published in Carrara: The Marble Quarries of Tuscany (Stanford University Press, 1999).
  - Sub-series 1. 20 x 24 inch silver gelatin prints, 1987-1994
    20 gelatin silver prints enlarged from 4x5 inch negatives; 20x24 inches.
    - Artisan, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - View of Fantiscritti, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - View of Colonnata, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Underground Quarry Workmen, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Gioia Quarry Workman, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Underground Quarry (Sisyphus), 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Quarry Peak, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Quarry Entrance, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Patio with Chairs, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Non Accendate Fuochi nel Boschi, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View from Gioia Quarry, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Levi Jacket, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Infirmary, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Calendars, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Workers at Monte Altissima, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Quarry at Campocecina, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Storage Sheds, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Quarry Pit at Fantiscritti, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Incline, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series 2. 8 x 10 inch silver gelatin prints, 1987-1994
    Fourty-four high gloss gelatin silver press printed in Carrara: The Marble Quarries of Tuscany (Stanford, Calif.: Stanford University Press, 1999).
    - Carrara marble quarry phtoographs, 1987-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6-10)
- Series 2. Europe and Mexico, 1994-2002
  Travels in Europe and Mexico: 11 gelatin silver prints enlarged from 4x5 inch negatives; 16x20 inches; sepia toned.
  - Monk at Cells of Saint Francis, 1994 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 1)
  - Barber (Real de Catorce, Mexico), 1996 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 1)
  - Child’s Grave (Real de Catorce, Mexico), 1996 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 1)
  - #99-12 (Church, Real de Catorce, Mexico), 1999 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 1)
  - Funeral Parlor, Guanajuato, Mexico, 1999 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 1)
  - Blasted Cactus (Real de Catorce, Mexico), 1996 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 2)
  - Quarry Remnant, Matera, 2002 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 2)
  - Courtyard, Matera, 2000 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 2)
  - Wall Decorations, Craco, Italy, 2002 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 2)
  - Matera #00-61, 2000 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 2)
  - Matera #00-65, 2000 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 2)
- Series 3. Rapture series, Rome, and the Pantheon, 1987-2006
  10 color ink jet prints on Epson Hot Press Bright; 17x 24 inches.
  - 03308 (spongebob), 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 3)
  - 00976 (rapturous man), 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 3)
  - 01173 (selfie), 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 3)
  - 01430 (man shielding his eyes), 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 3)
  - 00903 (paisley dress), 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 3)
  - 01231 (two men, Renaissance light), 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 4)
  - 01049 (image on announcement0, 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 4)
  - 03203.2 (rapturous woman), 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 4)
  - 01487 (boy with wings), 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 4)
  - 01477.2 (la dolce vita), 2012 (Flat-boxes 2, Folder 4)
- Series 4. American travel, 1979-1992
  46 gelatin silver prints from travels in Connecticut and California.
  - Sub-series 1. Scott Creek, 1986-1992
    - Scott Creek #60, 92-04, 16, 92-17, 36, 92-29, 92-17, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Scott Creek #92-39, 20, 109, 65, 105, 92-36, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series 2. Connecticut and California images, 1979-1986
    - Old Brewery, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Farm River #1, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Marine Railway, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Low Reservoir, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Johnson’s Oyster Farm, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - View of Crockett, California, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Sandblaster, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Crockett, California, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Boone Lake #2, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Seymour, Connecticut, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ray at Home, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - View from Ray’s House, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Dry Gulch Ranch, Santa Cruz, California, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Johnson’s Boat Yard, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Derby, Connecticut, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Bridge at Albion, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Samoa, California, circa 1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Stony Creek Quarry, Connecticut, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Farm River Benches, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Boone Lake #1, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Albion River Mouth, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Albion River Mouth (print on Kodak Azo), 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Branford River, Connecticut, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Terry Hunting Mushrooms, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Stunted Redwoods, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Momauguin, Connecticut, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mr. Brown’s Porch, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Lamphier’s Cove (with dog), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Yuba River, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - San Juan Bautista, Calfiornia, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - View of Davenport, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Series 5. Garden images, 1987-2006
  Garden series; includes Matera. 21 ink jet prints on Hahnemuhle photo Rag and Hahnemuhle William Turner; 20x24 inches.